Guide to the Joani Blank papers, circa 1989-1999.
Blank, Joani papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Joani Blank papers, circa 1989-1999.
7827
Blank, Joani,
3 cubic feet.
Audio recordings, correspondence, legal documents, manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Office files, videotape, posters, copies of articles by others, and books reflecting Blank's work and interests as a sex educator and owner of Down There Press and Good Vibrations. Included are many articles by Susie Bright and Annie Sprinkle.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Sex educator and founder of Good Vibrations, the first sex-positive, woman-friendly adult store in the United States, with branches in San Francisco and Berkeley, California. Blank also wrote A kid's first book about sex and The playbook for kids about sex, and founded Down There Press.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Office files, videotape, posters, copies of articles by others, and books reflecting Blank's work and interests as a sex educator and owner of Down There Press and Good Vibrations. Included are many articles by Susie Bright and Annie Sprinkle.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Blank, Joani, 1937-; Blank, Joani, 1937-; Bright, Susie, 1958-; Sprinkle, Annie, 1954-; Down There Press.; Good Vibrations (Firm)
Subjects:
Sex instruction -- United States.; Sex educators -- United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Books are to be cataloged individually.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Files
Series II. Audio Visual Material
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Files
  - Coop- Briarpatch articles, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Claude Whitmyer (Briarpatch), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Faces video releases and correspondence with actors, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Faces miscellaneous, including some newcomers, 1995, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Scan of Good Vibrations Guide to Vibrators copy, signed, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Better Sex Vids/Steve Kapelow, 1991, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "How to Use a Vibrator" video notes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Great Vibes finances, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - DTP- COAs, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Includes one sheet of slides
  - Great Vibes pilot, customer feedback, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Frankfurt contacts, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Amsterdam contacts, receipts, notes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Art Unlimited, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - SACU- 2nd Selfhelp, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Workshop: Fair Fight Rituals, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Sexuality Resources, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Book ideas that never happened: Dear Owner, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Book ideas that never happened: Joani's Kid's Books, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Book ideas that never happened: Tyranny, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Susie Bright, 1992-1999 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Betty Dodson- Liberating Masturbation, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Marcy Sheiner clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Carol Queen clippings, 1994, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Annie Sprinkle clippings, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Marco Vassi's Diaries, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Jack Morin, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Michael Rosen, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Isadora Alman, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - David Steinberg, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Ginu Kamani and Indian, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - I Am My Lover, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - I Am My Lover, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - I Am My Lover photo submissions, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - I Am My Lover Annie Sprinkle Rejects and negatives, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Show Me, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Censorship, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - I Am My Lover: Model's Words, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Intro to I Am My Lover, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - IAML: Photographer Bio, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - IASHS, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Kinsey Institute, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - SFSI, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Journal of Sexuality and Relationships, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Batteries Not Included, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Antique vibrator file, 1989-1997 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Antique vibrators for sale, 1992, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Includes pictures
  - Antique vibrators with Phyllis Christopher note, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - "Sexual Aid for Women, Based on Consumer Research" Ireen Laarakker, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Russell Wilcox, Joani's sex toy design, undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - The World, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - JB interview in GV gazette, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - GV Gazette, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - GV store news, 2004-2006 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - JB press releases, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Good Vibrations catalogs, 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - GV Catalog covers, 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - GV Press releases, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Store Internships, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Passion Flower, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Other Sex Shops, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - GV East Bay Store, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Legal battles and papers related to conversion to coop, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Joani Blank memos, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - OE- promo, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Worker/Owner articles, 1987, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Worker ownership, 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Timline of Worker-owner coop, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - OE as Coop, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Biz History, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - History of OE, 1989, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - AYS: About Your Sexuality, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Vibrator Survey, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bibliographies, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Cupido Sex Fair, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Workshop, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Aging and Sexuality, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Women's sexuality workshop, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Telling your Story workshop, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Sexual Assertiveness workshop, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Possible places for GLGS, 1994, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Workshop exercises, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Eve's secrets revealed workshop, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Workshop ideas, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Joani's 60th birthday party, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1995 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cover My Ass, 1985-1996 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Moscow, St. Petersburg, Russia, China, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Indian Sex articles, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Celebrate the Self, 1993-1998 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Masturbation, 1997-1999 (Box 2, Folder 58-59)
  - Good Vibrations workshop poster, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Articles
  - Miscellaneous sex, 1989-1998 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Sex and aging, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Harry Stanley, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Challenging Georgia's obscenity law, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Sex trauma, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Sexuality miscelleaneous, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Transgender, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Articles to pass on- Sexuality, 1998-2003 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - AIDS/HIV, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Christian Coalition, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Anal Stuff/Bolling, Brecher, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Circumcision, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Porn, 1992, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Erotica, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Kids and Sex, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Life and Death, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Non-monogamy/poly love, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence/regional officers, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Sex and Judaism, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Down There Press
  - Book Reviews, 1993, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - SDI Promotions, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1983, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Contract, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Book covers (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Status reports, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - First Person Sexual, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Consulting form letter, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Media Coaching, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Yes Press Catalog, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Rejects--Sandy Watt, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Joani's Website, 1999-2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Covers and photos, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - FBI Freedom of Information on Joani Blank, 1959, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Herotica Audiotape, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - America Latina, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Exhibitionism for Shy, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Femalia, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Herotica film/TV, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Sex info: Isadora, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Call for submissions, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Herotica 4, 1994, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Series II. Audio Visual Material
  - Good Vibrations: The Complete Video Guide to Vibrators, 1993; V-9266 (Box 3)
  - Optomen Television: The Clitoris Uncovered, January 27, 2000; V-9267 (Box 3)
  - Midori, July 10, 1997; V-9268 (Box 3)
  - Faces of Ecstasy, V-9269 (Box 3)
  - Susan Block Show: Women on Top, 1993; V-9270 (Box 3)
  - Carol Queen's Great Vibrations: An Explicit Guide to Vibrators, V-9271 (Box 3)
  - Orgasm! The faces of Ecstasy, 2003; V-9272 (Box 3)
  - Zen Pussy, V-9273 (Box 3)
  - Faces of Ecstasy, 1998; V-9274 (Box 3)
  - GLI 1: Clara/Monroe, April 3, 2003; V-9275 (Box 3)
  - GLI 2: Sylvia, April 3, 2003; V-9276 (Box 3)
  - GLI 3: Silvia, April 3, 2003; V-9277 (Box 3)
  - GLI 4: Silvia, April 3, 2003; V-9278 (Box 3)
  - GLI 5: Bill and Desiree, April 3, 2003; V-9279 (Box 3)
  - GLI 6: Desiree, April 3, 2003; V-9280 (Box 3)
  - GLI 7: Joani, Bill Noble, April 3, 2003; V-9281 (Box 3)
  - GLI 8, April 3, 2003; V-9282 (Box 3)
  - GLI 9: Dan and Stephanie, April 4, 2003; V-9283 (Box 3)
  - GLI 10: Michael Rosenbaum, April 4, 2003; V-9284 (Box 3)
  - GLI 11: Michael/Cecilia, April 5, 2003; V-9285 (Box 3)
  - GLI 12: Jenny, Vino, April 5, 2003; V-9286 (Box 3)
  - GLI 13: Denise/Leo, Greg, April 5, 2003; V-9287 (Box 3)
  - GLI 14: Denise/Leo, April 5, 2003; V-9288 (Box 3)
  - GLI 15: Greg, April 5, 2003; V-9289 (Box 3)
  - GLI 16: Molly, April 6, 2003; V-9290 (Box 3)
  - GLI 17: Carol Q, April 6, 2003; V-9291 (Box 3)
  - GLI 18: Scott, April 6, 2003; V-9292 (Box 3)
  - GLI 19: Jukie, April 6, 2003; V-9293 (Box 3)
  - GLI 20: Interview with Andy and Guy, April 6, 2003; V-9294 (Box 3)
  - GLI 21: Andy/Guy, April 6, 2003; V-9295 (Box 3)
  - GLI 22: Bob Nicol, April 7, 2003; V-9296 (Box 3)
  - GLI 23: Juba, April 7, 2003; V-9297 (Box 3)
  - GLI 24: Juba/ David Stein, April 7, 2003; V-9298 (Box 3)
  - GLI 25: David Stein, Joani Blank, April 7, 2003; V-9299 (Box 3)
  - GLI 26: Joani Voice Qs, April 7, 2003; V-9300 (Box 3)
  - XLI 1: Clara Monroe, April 3, 2003; V-9301 (Box 3)
  - XLI 2: Sylvia, April 3, 2003; V-9302 (Box 3)
  - XLI 3: Sylvia end, April 3, 2003; V-9303 (Box 3)
  - XLI Orig: Bill/Desiree, April 3, 2003; V-9304 (Box 3)
  - XLI Orig: Bill end, Dan Interview, April 3, 2003; V-9305 (Box 3)
  - XLI Orig: Dan/Steph, April 4, 2003; V-9306 (Box 3)
  - XLI Orig: Desiree, Joani, April 4, 2003; V-9307 (Box 3)
  - XLI Orig: Dan/Steph end, April 4, 2003; V-9308 (Box 3)
  - XLI 1, April 5, 2003; V-9309 (Box 3)
  - XLI 2: Michael, Cecilia, Vibe tone, April 5, 2003; V-9310 (Box 3)
  - XLI 3: Jenny, April 5, 2003; V-9311 (Box 3)
  - XLI 5: Denise, Leo, Greg, April 5, 2003; V-9312 (Box 3)
  - XLI 6: Denise et al, April 5, 2003; V-9313 (Box 3)
  - XLI 7: End group, April 5, 2003; V-9314 (Box 3)
  - XLI 1: Molly and tone, April 6, 2003; V-9315 (Box 3)
  - XLI 2: Carol, April 6, 2003; V-9316 (Box 3)
  - XLI 3: Scott/Kate, April 6, 2003; V-9317 (Box 3)
  - XLI 4: Jukie End, April 6, 2003; V-9318 (Box 3)
  - XLI 5: Andrea Guy, April 6, 2003; V-9319 (Box 3)
  - XLI 1: Bob, April 7, 2003; V-9320 (Box 3)
  - XLI 2, April 7, 2003; V-9321 (Box 3)
  - XLI 3: David, April 7, 2003; V-9322 (Box 3)
  - Orgasm! The Faces of Ecstasy, 2004; DVD-1888 (Box 3)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books catalogued individually
Anal Pleasure and Health, Jack Morin. 2010.
Anal Pleasure and Health, Jack Morin. 1986.
Anal Pleasure and Health, Jack Morin. 1998. Signed.
Aural Sex and Verbal Intercourse, Isadora Alman. 1984.
Femalia, Joani Blank, editor. 1993Signed.
Herotica 1, Susie Bright, editor. 1988.
Herotica 2, Susie Bright and Joani Blank, editors. 1992.
Herotica 3, Susie Bright, editor. 1994.
Herotica 5, Marcy Sheiner, editor. 1998.
Herotica 6, Marcy Sheiner, editor. 1999.
A Kid's First Book About Sex, Joani Blank and Marcia Quakenbush. 1986.
A Kid's First Book About Sex, Joani Blank and Marcia Quakenbush. 1983.
Sex Spoken Here, Carol Queen and Jack Davis, editors. 1998.
First Person Sexual, Joani Blank, editor. 1996.
Any 2 People, Kissing, Kate Dominic. 2003.
Herotica, Susie Bright, editor. 1988In Dutch.
In Piacere Negato, Jack Morin. 1994.
Still Doing It: women and men over 60 write about their sexuality, Joani Blank, editor. 2000.
Good Vibrations: the Complete Guide to Vibrators, Joani Blank. 1982.
Good Vibrations: the Complete Guide to Vibrators, revised, Joani Blank. 1982.
Good Vibrations: the Complete Woman's Guide to Vibrators, Joani Blank. 1976.
Sex Toy Tales, Joani Blank. 1997.
My First Vibrator: True Life Vibrator Tales, Joani Blank. 1992.
Period, JoAnn Gardner-Loulan, Bonnie Lopez, Marcia Quackenbush. 1979.
Period, revised, JoAnn Gardner-Loulan, Bonnie Lopez, Marcia Quackenbush. 1981.
The Big Book of Masturbation: From Angst to Zeal, Martha Cornog. 2003.
Period, JoAnn Gardner-Loulan, Bonnie Lopez, Marcia Quackenbush. In Japanese.
Die Regel, JoAnn Gardner-Loulan, Bonnie Lopez, Marcia Quackenbush. 1979. In German.
Ongesteld, JoAnn Gardner-Loulan, Bonnie Lopez, Marcia Quackenbush. 1979.
Periodo, JoAnn Gardner-Loulan, Bonnie Lopez, Marcia Quackenbush. 1986. In Spanish.
The Playbook for Women about Sex, Joani Blank. 1979.
The Playbook for Women about Sex, Joani Blank. 1975.
The Playbook for Men about Sex, Joani Blank. 1975.
The Playbook for Men about Sex, Joani Blank. 1981.
The Playbook for Men about Sex, Joani Blank. 1976.
Cunt Coloring Book, Joani Blank. 1975.
I Am My Lover, Joani Blank and Honey Lee Cottrell. 1978.
The Sensuous Coloring Book, Patricia Waters. 1980.
The Playbook for Kids about Sex, Joani Blank. 1990.
The Playbook for Kids about Sex, Joani Blank. 1980Three copies..
Photo Sex: Fine Art Sexual Photography Comes of Age, David Steinberg, editor. 2003.
The Good Vibrations Guide to Sex, Cathy Winks, Anne Semans. 2002.
Good Vibrations: the New Complete Guide to Vibrators, Joani Blank. 2000.
The Good Vibrations guide: the G-Spot, Cathy Winks.
I Am My Lover, Joani Blank, editor. 1997.
Erotic by Nature, David Steinberg, editor. 1995.
San Francisco: Love and Sex, 2015.
Zeig Mal Mehr, Will McBride.